{
    "id": "ecbaaba726ee4112b36d1e67343bdb35",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He told me that he …………………………… me the other day.",
            "description": "A past tense in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "has seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ……………………… permit that.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "won't",
                "wouldn't",
                "can't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The father told his son that he …………………………… him a nice gift.",
            "description": "Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "bought",
                "has bought",
                "had bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "My uncle told me that he ……………………… me a laptop.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "shall buy"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he ………………………….. to move to Singapore.",
            "description": "A simple present tense in the direct speech becomes simple past tense in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "wanted",
                "wants",
                "has wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher advised them ……………………….. hard.",
            "description": "Imperatives are reported with a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "that work",
                "to work"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Sonia told Mathew that she ……………………………. all of her friends.",
            "description": "Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "has invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager told me that if I ………………………...... another deadline I would be sacked.",
            "description": "A simple present in the direct speech becomes simple past in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "miss",
                "missed",
                "have missed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The father told his son that he ……………………………… his parents.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has to obey",
                "had to obey",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he ……………………………… a strange experience the previous day.",
            "description": "Had had is the past perfect of had. ",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "had had",
                "has had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I reminded him that his mother …………………………. for him anxiously.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will be waiting",
                "would be waiting",
                "can be waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The cop asked the man where ………………………….. going.",
            "description": "Indirect questions have the normal word order. ",
            "answers": [
                "was he",
                "he was"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}